Barbara Dane collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Barbara Dane collection 1952-1978
AFC 1980/001
Dane, Barbara, collector.; Silber, Irwin, 1925-2010, collector.
approximately 458 items
43 sound tape reels: analog, various speeds; 10 in.
80 sound tape reels: analog, various speeds; 7 in.
35 sound tape reels: analog, various speeds; 5 in.
6 folders; 5 linear inches; 1 container
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of sound recordings of interviews, readings by authors, lectures and speeches, and radio broadcasts with songs and music, recorded and compiled by Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber for the Sing Out! radio program on WBAI-FM, New York City; and for other radio shows and documentation of other music and events from 1952-1978. Includes interviews with Vietnam War protesters, draft resisters, and topical songs written about the Vietnam War; many songs about other events of the 1960s and 1970s, including the African American civil rights movement; Native American survival movement; the women's rights and gay rights movements. The collection includes some tapes submitted by performers or listeners of Barbara Dane's shows, some with accompanying letters. Includes interview and songs performed by Catalan poet and composer, Raimon; Philippine songs; Cambodian songs; sound recordings of the Poor People's March on Washington, 1968; folk festivals and other recordings.
Provenance
Barbara Dane; 1981.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Barbara Dane collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Barbara Dane was born May 12, 1927, and raised in Detroit, Michigan. She is a folk, blues, and jazz singer, and co-founder of Paredon Records with her husband Irwin Silber. Paredon published songs, poetry, and oratory related to social and political activism. Throughout her life, Dane sang at demonstrations in Washington, D.C., and in small towns all over the U.S. and the world. During the 1950s and 60s, she performed and recorded with many great musicians from Earl Hines to Willie Dixon. She appeared on national TV’s Timex Jazz Show with Louis Armstrong. In 1966, Dane became the first American musician to tour post-revolutionary Cuba. In February 2018, the Smithsonian Folkways released a 2-CD retrospective, Hot Jazz, Cool Blues and Hard-Hitting Songs along with her historic folkways LP, Barbara Dane and the Chambers Brothers. On her 85th birthday, The Boston Globe music critic James Reed called her "one of the true unsung heroes of American music."
Scope and Content
Collection of sound recordings of interviews, readings by authors, lectures and speeches, and radio broadcasts with songs and music, recorded and compiled by Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber for the Sing Out! radio program on WBAI-FM, New York City; and for other radio shows and documentation of other music and events from 1952-1978. Includes interviews with Vietnam War protesters, draft resisters, and topical songs written about the Vietnam War; many songs about other events of the 1960s and 1970s, including the African American civil rights movement; Native American survival movement; the women's rights and gay rights movements. The collection includes some tapes submitted by performers or listeners of Barbara Dane's shows, some with accompanying letters. Includes interview and songs performed by Catalan poet and composer, Raimon; Philippine songs; Cambodian songs; sound recordings of the Poor People's March on Washington, 1968; folk festivals and other recordings.
Arrangement
The Barbara Dane collection is organized in two series:
Series 1: Manuscripts
Series 2: Sound recordings, 1952-1978
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Barry, Margaret, 1917-1989; Bikel, Theodore; Carawan, Guy; Cohen, John, 1932-2019; Cooney, Michael B., 1943-; Cray, Ed; Dane, Barbara; Dixon, Willie, 1915-1992; Fuller, Jesse; Garland, Jim, 1905-1978; Gorman, Michael, 1895-1970; Hopkins, Lightnin', 1912-1982; Jackson, Mahalia, 1911-1972; Johnson, Lonnie, 1894-1970; Kraber, Tony; Lebrón, Lolita, 1919-2010; Lester, Julius, 1939-2018; Lipscomb, Mance, 1895-1976; Lynn, Conrad J.; McDonald, Joe, 1942-; McDowell, Fred; McGhee, Brownie, 1915-1996; Melton, Barry; Memphis Slim; Miller, Big; Paxton, Tom, 1937-; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980; Raimon, 1940-; Seeger, Pete, 1919-2014; Silber, Irwin, 1925-2010; Smith, Harry Everett, 1923-1991; Traum, Happy; Watson, Doc; Williams, Big Joe, 1903-1982; Witherspoon, Jimmy; Yancey, Estella
Organizations
Chambers Brothers; Miramichi Folksong Festival.; WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.); Weavers (Musical group)
Subjects
Blues (Music)--1951-1960.; Blues (Music)--1961-1970.; Blues musicians--United States--Interviews.; Civil Rights movements--United States--History--20th century--Songs and music.; Folk festivals--United States.; Folk music--United States.; Political ballads and songs.; Poor People's Campaign.; Protest songs--United States.; Topical songs.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements--United States.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Songs and music.
Places
New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Folk music radio programs.; Interviews.; Radio programs.; Sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Administrative materials (Box-folder 1/1)
    Contains the collection inventory, tape concordance, original tape inventory, and list of Sing Out radio programs with dates and guests.
    - Terry Lipscomb, Texas, AFC 1980/001: SR151; 1 empty tape box
      Tape box decorated by artwork. See Terry Lipscomb, Texas sound recording, AFC 1980/001: SR151 for related materials.
  - Photocopies of tape boxes SR01-SR30 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Photocopies of tape boxes SR31-SR75 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Photocopies of tape boxes SR76-SR105 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Photocopies of tape boxes SR106-SR140 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Photocopies of tape boxes SR141-SR157 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Series 2: Sound recordings
  - Katherine Ann Porter reads, Pale Horse, Pale Rider, December 8, and December 15, 1952, December 8, 1952; AFC 1980/001: SR001; RXB 0001; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Katherine Ann Porter reads, Pale Horse, Pale Rider, from Caedmon recording made in NYC.
  - Julian Lee Rayford, September 10, 1955, AFC 1980/001: SR002; RXB 0002; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Julian Lee Rayford performs street cries, Mike Fink songs, Mike Fink's Bragg Paul Bunyan chant, the Buttermilk Pipeline, Davy Crockett chant, story from Crockett Almanac, and Colonel Crockett's Morning Hunt.
  - The Weavers, 1958, AFC 1980/001: SR003; RXB 0003; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    The Weavers interview themselves about their origins and discuss cuts from their Carnegie Hall Concert record. The interview was done for Barbara Dane's KPFA program.
  - Miramichi Folk Festival, part 1-3, 1959, AFC 1980/001: SR004-SR006; RWC 6401 - RWC 6403; 3 audiotape reels, 10 in.
    List of songs on box.
  - British Isles - Paul Phillips and Barry Hall, 1959, AFC 1980/001: SR007; RXB 0004; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Urreal "Little Brother" Montgomery 1959, AFC 1980/001: SR008; RXB 0005; 1 audiotape reel, 7-in.
    Montgomery made this tape for Barbara Dane in Chicago.
  - Willie Dixon and Urreal "Little Brother" Montgomery, 1959, AFC 1980/001: SR009; RXB 0006; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Willie Dixon, Chicago blues writer and singer, sings the blues and other things accompanied by Urreal "Little Brother" Montgomery.
  - "From Here to Sunday," Ed Cray's program, February 27, 1960 and July 31, 1959, AFC 1980/001: SR010; RXB 0007; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Interview with Mahalia Jackson and Barbara Dane, by Ed Cray on his program, From Here to Sunday in Los Angeles at KPFK. Interview with Memphis Slim, February 27, 1960 and July 31, 1959.
  - Big Joe Williams, July 1960, AFC 1980/001: SR011; RXB 0008; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Big Joe Williams at Ash Grove, Los Angeles music club. He also talks about his life and work.
  - Lightning Sam Hopkins, interview KPFX, 1960, AFC 1980/001: SR012 - SR013; RXB 0009 - RXB 0010; 2 audiotape reels, 7 in.
    Interview on reels 1-2.
  - Barbara Dane interviews Big Miller, July 8, 1961, AFC 1980/001: SR014; RXB 0011; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Barbara Dane interviews Big Miller, blues singer from Kansas City.
  - Barbara Dane interviews Mance Lipscomb, part 1-3, 1961, AFC 1980/001: SR015 - SR017; RXB 0012 - RXB 0014; 3 audiotape reels, 7 in.
    SR015: Barbara Dane interviews Mance Lipscomb about his 55 years of sharecropping in Navasota, Texas, 1961.
    SR016: Barbara Dane interviews Mance Lipscomb about his life and work in Navasota, Texas, 1961.
    SR017: Barbara Dane interviews Mance Lipscomb for a radio show, includes songs, 1961.
  - Barbara Dane interviews Fred McDowell, 1960s, AFC 1980/001: SR018; RXB 0015; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Barbara Dane interviews Fred McDowell, Mississippi blues singer, early 1960s.
  - Barbara Dane interviews Fred McDowell, 1960s, AFC 1980/001: SR019; RXB 0016; 1 audiotape reel, 7-in.
  - Tony Kraber-I, April 16, 1962, AFC 1980/001: SR020; RXB 0017; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    List of songs on tape box.
  - Tony Kraber-II, April 16, 1962, AFC 1980/001: SR021; RXB 0018; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Tony Kraber-III, 1962, AFC 1980/001: SR022; RXB 0019; 1 audiotape reel, 7-in.
  - Pete Seeger, AFC 1980/001: SR023; RXB 0020; 1 audiotape reel, 7-in.
    Pete Seeger singing some topical songs from 1963-1964. List of songs in tape box.
  - Children's ring games and chants, July 1964 and Estella Hana Yancey, September 23, 1964, July 1967; AFC 1980/001: SR024; RXB 0021; 1 audiotape reel, 7-in.
    Tape includes children's ring games and chants. The balance of tape is with Estella Hana Yancey.
  - Miramichi Folk Festival, 1964, part 1, AFC 1980/001: SR025; RWC 6404; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Miramichi Folk Festival, 1964, part 3, AFC 1980/001: SR026; RWC 6405; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Miramichi Folk Festival, 1964, part 2, AFC 1980/001: SR027; RWC 6406; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Miramichi Folk Festival, 1964, part 4, AFC 1980/001: SR028; RWC 6407; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Interview with Estella Mama Yancey by Barbara Dane, September 23, 1964, AFC 1980/001: SR029; RXB 0022; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - From Here to Sunday with Barbara Dane, April 14, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR030; RWC 6408; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out with Barbara Dane, subject of the program is Woody Guthrie, April 14, 1965, 63 min. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Mance Lipscomp, April 15, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR031; RWC 6409; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Manse Lipscomp, April 15, 1965, 59:30 min. Pancake reel.
  - Unidentified, April 19, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR032; unassigned; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber, November 11, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR033; RWC 6410; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber with guest, Brownie McGhee, 60 min.
  - Sing-Out with Dane and Harry Smith, April 27, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR034; RWC 6411; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out with Dane and Harry Smith (editor of Folkway's famous Smith Anthology), April 27, 1965, 57:30 min. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out with Dane and lzzy Young, May 5, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR035; RWC 6412; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out with Dane, May 13, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR036; RWC 6443; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    New releases (folk) - No. 1, May 13, 1965, 60 min. Pancake reel.
  - Barbara Dane, "Is Bob Dylan really John Lennon?" May 25, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR037; RXB 0023; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Barbara Dane hosts Sing-Out No. 2, first broadcast in Sing-Out series called "Is Bob Dylan really John Lennon?" (music from selected records), May 25, 1965, 60 min.
  - Interview by Dane with Lonnie Johnson, May 25, 1965 part 1 of 2, AFC 1980/001: SR038; RXB 0024; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Interview by Dane with Lonnie Johnson, May 25, 1965, WBAI-NY, part 1 of 2.
  - Lonnie Johnson interview part 2, AFC 1980/001: SR039; RXB 0025; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber, "ls Bob Dylan really John Lennon?" May 25, 1965, part 2 of 2, AFC 1980/001: SR040; RXB 0026; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    First broadcast in the series Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber called "ls Bob Dylan really John Lennon?" May 25, 1965, part 2 of 2.
  - Silber interviews Dane, June 3, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR041; RWC 6413; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    List of songs on tape box. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out, June 22, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR042; RWC 6414; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out mangled by post office, the contents of program unknown, June 22, 1965. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out N.Y. Folk Festival, June 23, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR043; RWC 6415; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out N.Y. Folk Festival with Dane and Irwin Silber, June 23, 1965. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out show with Michael Cooney, Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber, November 6, 1965 Pancake reel., AFC 1980/001: SR044; RWC 6416; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out show WBAI-NY, with Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber and guest, Michael Cooney. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out, 1965 Newport Folk Festival, July 20, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR045; RWC 6417; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out, Dane at preview for 1965 Newport Folk Festival in Central Park's Delacorte Theater, July 20, 1965.
  - Sing in for Peace, produced by Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber, September 24, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR046; RXB 0027; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    A compilation of songs and comments submitted for use at the first big anti-Vietnam war demonstration in New York called, Sing in for Peace (produced by Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber) September 24, 1965, Carnegie Hall.
  - Barbara Dane Show with guests Guy Caravan and Tom Paxton, September 25, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR047; RWC 6418; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Barbara Dane Show, guests Guy Caravan and Tom Paxton, September 25, 1965. Pancake reel.
  - Barbara Dane and Chambers Brothers, September 15, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR048; RWC 6419; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Theo Bikel, Barbara Dane and Irvin Silber, September 1, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR049; RWC 6420; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out with Dane and Silber, September 8, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR050; RWC 6421; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out with Margaret Barry and Michael Gorman, part 1, September 15, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR051; RXB 0028; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Sing-Out with Margaret Barry and Michael Gorman, part 2, no date, AFC 1980/001: SR052; RXB 0029; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Sing-Out with Barbara Dane and Irwin Silber with guest Charles O'Hagerty, September 22, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR053; RWC 6422; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out, Dane and Silber interview with Frances Taylor about Bob Dylan, October 17, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR054; RWC 6423; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Margaret Barry and Michael Gorman, October 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR055; RXB 0030; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Sing-Out radio show, Dane and Silber interview with Frances Taylor about Bob Dylan, October 17, 1965.
  - Sing-Out, Dane and Silber, NYC's Big Black Out of 1965, November 10, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR056; RWC 6424; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out, commemorating death of Joe Hill, November 17, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR057; RWC 6425; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Sing-Out out on WBAI radio show commemorating death of Joe Hill, November 17, 1965. Pancake reel.
  - Sing-Out, WBAI radio show, Dane and Silber with Julius Lester, November 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR058; RWC 6426; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out, WBAI radio show, Dane and Silber, November 27, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR059; RWC 6427; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out, Dane and Silber, December 5, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR060; RWC 6428; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out with Silber children, December 19, 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR061; RWC 6429; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Duration of interview was 62:45 min.
  - Interview with Brownie McGhee, NYC, December 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR062; RXB 0031; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Jesse Fuller interview, NYC 1965, AFC 1980/001: SR063; RWC 6430; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Barbara Dane interviewing Jesse Fuller, 1965, NYC, AFC 1980/001: SR064; RWC 6431; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Christmas folk songs, January 2, 1966, AFC 1980/001: SR065; RWC 6432; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Christmas folk songs with commentary by Silber and Dane.
  - New Years Program, January 3, 1966, AFC 1980/001: SR066; RWC 6433; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    New Years program with Ewan MacCall, Brendon Behan, and The Singing Streets.
  - Doc Watson, guest on Sing-Out radio show UBAI, January 16, 1966, AFC 1980/001: SR067; RWC 6434; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out radio show WBAI with Dane and Silber on the 15th Anniversary of Sing-Out, February 3, 1966, AFC 1980/001: SR068; RWC 6435; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out, with guest John Cohen, February 15, 1966, AFC 1980/001: SR069; RWC 6436; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Sing-Out with Dane and Silber, and Happy Traum Finger Picking, March 1, AFC 1980/001: SR070; RWC 6437; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Dane and Sibler interview Happy Traum Finger Picking, 62 min.
  - Barbara's Blues' radio show from KPFK, interview with Jimmy Witherspoon, April 7, 1966, AFC 1980/001: SR071; RXB 0032; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Barbara's Blues' radio show from KPFK, Pacifica Station in Los Angeles, interview with Jimmy Witherspoon blues singer, with music from selected records, 12 min.
  - Tuli Kupferberg, anti-war songs, 1967, AFC 1980/001: SR072; RXB 0033; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    List of songs on back of tape box. Also has disc inside box.
  - Raimon interview, March 27, 1967, AFC 1980/001: SR073; RXB 0034; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    Raimon is a catalonian political singer.
  - Joe McDonald, Untitled protest no. 1, "Feel Like I'm Fixin' to Die", AFC 1980/001: SR074; RXB 0035; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    Letter enclosed in box.
  - German jokes, '67, AFC 1980/001: SR075; RXB 0036; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Topical songs, 1967-1968, AFC 1980/001: SR076; RXB 0037; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Miscellaneous topical songs which came in from a variety of sources during 1967-1968. List of songs on back and inside of tape box.
  - Mike Cooney, musician and draft resister interviewed by Irwin Silber, March 19, 1968, AFC 1980/001: SR077; RXB 0038; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Dennis Gaston, interviewed by Irwin Silber, March 10, 1968, part 1, AFC 1980/001: SR078; RXB 0039; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    Dennis Gaston, an ex-vista worker, anti-war, so called hippie interviewed by Irwin Silber.
  - Dennis Gaston, interviewed by Irwin Silber, March 10, 1968, part 2, AFC 1980/001: SR079; RXB 0040; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Country Joe McDonald and Barry Melton interviewed by Irwin Silber, March 5, 1968, NYC, AFC 1980/001: SR080; RXB 0041; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Country Joe McDonald and Barry Melton interviewed by Irwin Silber, March 5, 1968, NYC, AFC 1980/001: SR081; RXB 0042; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Interview with Irwin Silber, March 28, 1968, AFC 1980/001: SR082; RXB 0043; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    Irwin Silber discusses attitudes about social change, current events with son of a former Communist who himself is an ex-Berkeley student who stood outside events on that campus.
  - Oleo Strut interview G.I.'s at Fort Hood, Texas, July 6, 1968, part 1 of 2, AFC 1980/001: SR083; RXB 0044; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    Oleo Strut interview G.I.'s at Fort Hood, Texas talk about their experiences during Vietnam War, July 6, 1968.
  - G.I.'s at Fort Hood, Texas, July 6, 1968, part 2 of 2, AFC 1980/001: SR084; RXB 0045; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Fred Gardner, 1969-70, AFC 1980/001: SR085; RXB 0046; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - The Unknown Soldier, "What was his name," by Peggy Seeger and Tark Warshaw, January 30, 1970, AFC 1980/001: SR086; RXB 0047; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Draftee sings "Uncle Sam wants me as a Soldier," January 31, 1970, AFC 1980/001: SR087; RXB 0048; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Poetry Reading at the Marxist Institute, August 14, 1970, AFC 1980/001: SR088; RXB 0049; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
  - Beastly Times Eric and Kirk Cheyfitz, AFC 1980/001: SR089; RXB 0050; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Beastly Times Eric and Kirk Cheyfitz, song group in the Washington, DC area. List of songs on back of tape box.
  - Various commentaries on the Vietnam War by Vinnie McNamara August 16, 1972, AFC 1980/001: SR090; RXB 0051; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Various commentaries on the Vietnam War by Vinnie McNamara at Operation P.O.W. in Concord, Massachusetts, Bob Missa at Burlington, Vermont and Chris Coyle.
  - Commentaries by Jim Holmes at Dewey Canyon III in Washington, DC, AFC 1980/001: SR091; RXB 0052; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Topical songs from a variety of sources, 1971, AFC 1980/001: SR092; RXB 0053; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Miscellaneous topical songs from a variety of sources, 1971. Notes on inside of tape box.
  - Draft resistance trial and support statements, November 1971, AFC 1980/001: SR093; RXB 0054; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Draft resistance trial and support statements from active-duty G.I.'s, wounded veterans, and Gold star mothers.
  - Songs and history of Philippines, 1971, AFC 1980/001: SR094; RXB 0055; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    The songs are discussed and also some of the history of the Philippine. List of songs on back of tape box.
  - Red Star Singers, AFC 1980/001: SR095; RXB 0056; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    List of songs on back of tape box, and also on piece of paper inside box.
  - Music from Cambodia 1972, AFC 1980/001: SR096; RXB 0057; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Music from Cambodia sent to Isreal Young from Sihanouk government in Paris, 1972, 21 min.
  - On Public Affairs WBAI History of Irish people in music, poetry and theatre, 1972, AFC 1980/001: SR097; RXB 0058; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Haiti, 1972 (from Lionel) part 2, AFC 1980/001: SR098; RXB 0059; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Haiti, 1972 (from Lionel) part 1, AFC 1980/001: SR099; RXB 0060; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Red Star Singers, AFC 1980/001: SR100; RXB 0061; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    List of songs on back of tape box.
  - Songs recorded and composed by Tuli Kupferberg, AFC 1980/001: SR101; RXB 0062; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - New Harmony Sisterhood Band, February 8, 1975, AFC 1980/001: SR102; RXB 0063; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    New Harmony Sisterhood Band, Somerville, Kansas. List of songs on back of tape box.
  - Jim Garland sings songs and talks, April 30, 1975, AFC 1980/001: SR103; RXB 0064; 1 audiotape reel, 5 in.
    List of items on piece of paper in tape box.
  - Tape of Malvina Reynolds singing, "The Judge Said" January 12, 1978, AFC 1980/001: SR104; RXB 0065; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Tape in Dolby, 2:42 min.
  - Lolita Lebron, January 22, 1976, AFC 1980/001: SR105; RXB 0066; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
    Lolita Lebron, interview made duing the last year of confinement in Alderson, West Virginia, prison by Genoveva Clemente.
  - People's Peace Treaty, AFC 1980/001: SR106; RXB 0067; 1 audiotape reel, 7 in.
  - Barbara Dane and Chambers Brothers, AFC 1980/001: SR107; RWC 6438; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
  - Unidentified, AFC 1980/001: SR108; RWC 6439; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.
    Box mangled by post office no way to check present contents.
  - Unidentified Sing-Out program with, AFC 1980/001: SR109; RWC 6440; 1 audiotape reel, 10 in.